<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Miss Stats</string>
    <!--- Home Screen Tiles Titles and Subtitles -->
    <string-array name="scrap_item_title">
        <item>Meet Miss Stats</item>
        <item>What is Statistics?</item>
        <item>Your Toolbox</item>
        <item>Probability</item>
        <item>The Shape of Normality</item>
        <item>The Monty Hall Problem</item>
        <item>Quizzes</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="scrap_item_subtitle">
        <item>Your friendly neighborhood statistician</item>
        <item>Reality through data</item>
        <item>How to describe data</item>
        <item>The power of one</item>
        <item>We are all under a bell</item>
        <item>How to win a tv show</item>
        <item>Test your knowledge</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Meet Miss Stats Full Text -->
    <string name="meetMissStats_1">Your Friendly Neighborhood Statistician</string>
    <string name="meetMissStats_2"><b><i>Miss Stats</i></b> is the <i>Statistics teacher</i> everyone would be happy to meet, even who ignore what Statistics is. \n
    Her mission is to spread the knowledge of Statistics everywhere with simple and  effective words and above all with the help of many, many examples. \n
    Once, many years ago, I told her (I even don\'t remember about what): \n
    <i>\"Miss Stats, this is really impossible for me, this would never happen!\",</i>
   but she answered me, and I have never forgot it: \n
    <b><i>\"Nothing is impossible. There are only things extremely improbable\"</i></b>
   and then she calculated with extremely precision what my chance were.\n
     No problem, big or small, can scare Miss Stats, her motto is always: \n
    <b><i>\"Give me enough data and I will give you the solution\".\n</i> </b>
    Numbers, according to Miss Stats, are very often undervalued, somebody think they are useful only for calculating results,
        but this isn\'t true: if you observe them with attention,
    like a true detective, they can tell you incredible stories and disclose entire secret worlds. </string>
    <string name="meetMissStats_3">Follow Miss Stats through this app, you won\'t regret it!</string>

    <!-- What is Statitistc Full Text -->
    <string name="whatIsStatics_1">Reality Through Data</string>
    <string name="whatIsStatistics_2">According to Miss Stats, <b>Statistics</b> is the science that transforms huge collections of <b>data</b>, numerical and not numerical, in something that makes sense for a normal human being, something
that can tell you a story. \n
The first thing to do in Statistics is always the same: <b>collect data</b>, because data are the basis for every statistical story.
That\'s why statisticians ask people so many strange questions, like: \n
<i>\"What is your favorite ice cream flavor?\" \n</i>
<i>\"Do you buy more ice  cream in summer or in winter?\"</i> \n
Statisticians fill pages and pages of data, they study them from every point of view, they draw graphics showing the most preferred ice-creams and how many ice-creams are sold in
every season. \n
With data at hand, statisticians pass to the second phase: they must interpret the data, that\'s to say they must give them a meaning. This is the most difficult moment,
 the moment that divides artists (like Miss Stats) from amateurs. \n
 A statistical story could tell: <i>"Most of people eat much more ice-cream in Summer, especially chocolate and vanilla".</i>
 This kind of stories are really important: they are used to make things work properly. \n
 Imagine a world where the ice-cream flavors in your most trusted ice cream shop are decided by pure randomness and not by science.\n Terrible things could happen!
 In Summer your local vendor could run out of chocolate and vanilla ice creams. \nDo you know which are the feelings of someone who wants a chocolate ice cream and finds only carrot and broccoli ice creams?
 I suppose you don\'t: well, you can thank Statistics for this.
    </string>

    <!-- Your ToolBox  Text -->
    <string-array name="ToolboxArgumentTitles">
        <item>A Simple Sample</item>
        <item>Mean</item>
        <item>Minimum</item>
        <item>Maximum</item>
        <item>Lower Quartile</item>
        <item>Upper Quartile</item>
        <item>Five-number Summary</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="ToolboxDescriptions">
        <item> In Statistics if you want an answer to a question, the first thing to do is always collecting data.
  Suppose you want to know how many people own a cat or a dog where you live.\n
  You could try it the hard way: interview every person in your town and then sum the number of cat and dog owners.
  This way you would have the most accurate answer possible.\n
  If you live in a small village of a dozen of houses, maybe this is feasible, but in very big cities with millions of people,
  you could pass years only doing this single interview.
  In most of cases you really can\'t do millions of interviews.\n
  So how do statisticians do in these cases? \n
  They try to interview only a sample of the population. A sample is a smaller part of the total population.
  In simple words, instead of interviewing millions of possible cat and dog owners, they interview a very smaller number: maybe a thousand, or some hundreds.\n
  A sample is well chosen, when it is representative of the total population. Even if you can\'t interview everyone, you could try to interview many different kind
  of people, so your smaller sample is like a little version of your town: for example some pet owners are young, other are old, some live in big houses, other have small
  homes.\n
  If your sample is well chosen, you can apply the results you find to all the population in your town.
  If in your sample the cat and dog owners are 3 every ten people interviewed, than it\'s probable this true even for the other people you haven\'t interviewed.\n
  What a time-saving!</item>
        <item>Mean Description</item>
        <item>Minimum Description</item>
        <item>Maximum Description</item>
        <item>Lower Quartile Description</item>
        <item>Upper Quartile Description</item>
        <item>Five-numbers Summary</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
